Guide to the Philip Turner Papers, 1751-1858, 1881 and undated RL.01315
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Turner Family Papers Series, 1776-1840, 1881 and undated, 3 folders
  Contains correspondence, financial and legal papers, and poetry. The majority of the series is addressed to or stems from John Turner and Nancy Turner, two of Philip Turner's children. Some of the material is related to the efforts of John Turner and John Turner Wait (Philip Turner's grandson) to receive compensation for Turner's Revolutionary War service. Judith Sargent Murray, American essayist and advocate for women's rights, and her husband, John Murray, were friends of the Turners and wrote mainly of family matters as well as one letter from Sargent Murray about the forthcoming publication of her book The Gleaner. The Financial and Legal Papers Subseries includes material from the Department of the Interior Pension Office arranged in original order, as well as the 1812 will for Mehitabel Waterman, of which John Turner is one of the executors. The Writings Subseries includes undated and unsigned poetry and eulogies.
  - Correspondence, 1786-1840, 1881 and undated (1 folder)
    - Letter, 8 Sept., 1786, from J. Sargent Murray, Gloucester, Mass., to Mrs. (Lucy) Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 22 Aug., 1792, from Julia Maria, to Anna Maria Sargent (Box 5)
    - Letter, 3 Nov., 1797, from J. Sargent Murray, Boston, to Nancy Turner, Norwich (Box 5)
    - Letter, 31 July, 1803, from Eliza A. Pinckney, Charleston, to Nancy Turner, New York (Box 5)
    - Letter, 31 June, 1810, from Geo. Turner to John Turner, Norwich (Box 5)
    - Letter, 31 Mar., 1825, from John Turner, Norwich, to Alexander Richards, Waddington, NY (Box 5)
    - Letter, 18 Sept., 1825, from Mary to Abby Maria Lathrop, New York (Box 5)
    - Letter, 22 Feb., 1826, from John Turner to Alexander Richards, Waddington, NY (Box 5)
    - Ms., 1 May, 1839, Company Orders, 7th Company, 18th Regiment Connecticut Milita (Box 5)
    - Ms., 29, Aug., 1840, Company Orders, 7th Company, 18th Regiment Infantry (Box 5)
    - Letter, 1881, from William McCrady, Cobb, Wis., to John Wait (Box 5)
    - Letter, undated, from John Murray, Boston, to Nancy Turner, Gloucester, Mass. (Box 5)
    - Letter, undated, from Robert Leckie, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, undated, from Philip Turner, to Mrs. King (Box 5)
    - Blank letterhead, Sayles & Welles Cotton Brokers, Norwich, Conn. (Box 5)
  - Financial and legal papers, 1776-1838 and undated (1 folder) (Box 5)
  - Writings, undated (1 folder) (Box 5)
- War of 1812 Series, 1812-1815, 1830-1831, and undated, 2 folders and 1 box
  Chiefly consists of correspondence relating to Turner's work at Ft. Columbus, in particular the acquisition of supplies and matters relating to Turner's pay. During this period, Turner also attempted to secure a commission. Turner was informed of his appointment as surgeon to the 1st Regiment of Artillery in February 1813, but, as the material in this series shows, an administrative error concerning his first name held up the issuing of his commission. In an effort to correct this mistake, Turner corresponded with Amos Stoddard (Major of the Artillery Corps at Fort Columbus), Henry Dearborn, William Simmons, John Armstrong Jr. (Secretary of War, 1813-1814), Daniel Parker (Chief Clerk of the War Department), and Joseph B. Varnum. Turner also wrote six letters to James Madison and two to James Monroe (then Secretary of War) on the issue of his commission. Turner's commission did not arrive before his death in 1815.
  - Letters, 1812-1815 and undated
    - Letter, 31 Mar., 1812, from Philip Turner, to Amos Stoddard, Fort Columbus (Box 5)
    - Letter, 17 Apr., 1812, from Philip Turner, New York, to Henry Dearborn (Box 5)
    - Letter, 24 June, 1812, from Amos Stoddard, Washington, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 27 June, 1812, from Philip Turner, Fort Columbus, New York, to Amos Stoddard (Box 5)
    - Letter, 9 July, 1812, from Amos Stoddard, Washington, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 14 July, 1812, from Philip Turner, Fort Columbus, New York, to Amos Stoddard (Box 5)
    - Letter, 29 Sept., 1812, from William Simmons, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 31 Dec., 1812, from General Armstrong, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 4 Jan., 1813, from Philip Turner, to John Armstrong (Box 5)
    - Letter, 5 Jan., 1813, from Charles Gardner, New York (on behalf of John Armstrong), to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 10 Jan., 1813, from William Eustis, New York, to James Monroe (Box 5)
    - Letter, 11 Jan., 1813, from Philip Turner, New York, to Daniel Parker (Box 5)
    - Letter, 5 Feb., 1813, from Philip Turner, New York, to John Armstrong (Box 5)
    - Letter, 12 Feb., 1813, from Daniel Parker, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 11 Mar., 1813, from Philip Turner, New York, to Daniel Parker (Box 5)
    - Letter, 24 Mar., 1813, from Philip Turner, New York, to William Simmons (Box 5)
    - Letter, 26 Mar., 1813, from Philip Turner, to John Armstrong (Box 5)
    - Letter, Apr., 1813, from unknown, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 1 Apr., 1813, from Thomas Chrystie, New York, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 3 Apr., 1813, from Philip Turner, to William Simmons (Box 5)
    - Letter, 3 Apr., 1813, from Philip Turner, to George Izard (Box 5)
    - Letter, 5 Apr., 1813, from Philip Turner, New York, to Francis Le Baron (Box 5)
    - Letter, 7 Apr., 1813, from Philip Turner, New York, to Francis Le Baron (Box 5)
    - Letter, 10 Apr., 1813, from Thomas Tudor Tucker, Washington, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 18 Apr., 1813, from Philip Turner, to John Armstrong (Box 5)
    - Letter, 18 Apr., 1813, from Philip Turner, Fort Columbus, to Daniel Parker (Box 5)
    - Letter, 29 May, 1813, from Samuel Ackerly to unknown (Box 5)
    - Letter, 4 June, 1813, from Philip Turner, Fort Columbus, to Daniel Parker (Box 5)
    - Letter, 14 June, 1813, from Philip Turner, to George Izard (Box 5)
    - Letter, 10 June, 1813, from Philip Turner, to George Izard (Box 5)
    - Letter, 24 July, 1813, from Philip Turner, to George Izard (Box 5)
    - Letter, 28 July, 1813, from Philip Turner, Fort Columbus, to James Madison (Box 5)
    - Letter, 5 Aug., 1813, from Samuel Ackerly, New York, to Philip Turner, Fort Columbus (Box 5)
    - Letter, 7 Aug., 1813, from Philip Turner, to Captain Hanham (Box 5)
    - Letter, 11 Aug., 1813, from Philip Turner, to Samuel Ackerly (Box 5)
    - Letter, 13 Aug., 1813, from Philip Turner, to Daniel Parker (Box 5)
    - Letter, 13 Aug., 1813, from Samuel Ackerly, New York, to Philip Turner, Fort Columbus (Box 5)
    - Letter, 20 Aug., 1813, from Philip Turner, to Samuel Ackerly (Box 5)
    - Letter, 26 Aug., 1813, from Samuel Ackerly, New York, to Philip Turner, Fort Columbus (Box 5)
    - Letter, 29 Aug., 1813, from Philip Turner, to Samuel Ackerly (Box 5)
    - Letter, 30 Aug., 1813, from Philip Turner, to Richard Cutts (Box 5)
    - Letter, 11 Sept., 1813, from unknown, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 13 Sept., 1813, from Thomas Chrystie, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 24 Sept., 1813, from John R. Fenwick, New York, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 1 Oct., 1813, from Colonel House, Fort Columbus, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 27 Dec., 1813, from Philip Turner, New York, to Joseph B. Varnum (Box 5)
    - Letter, 1 Jan., 1814, from Philip Turner, New York, to Mr. Bledsoe (Box 5)
    - Letter, 18 Jan., 1814, from Philip Turner, New York, to James Madison (Box 5)
    - Letter, 31 Jan., 1814, from Philip Turner, to John Armstrong (Box 5)
    - Letter, 1 Feb., 1814, from Philip Turner, to Daniel Parker (Box 5)
    - Letter, 5 Feb., 1814, from Philip Turner, to Joseph B. Varnum (Box 5)
    - Letter, 2 Mar., 1814, from Philip Turner, New York, to John Armstrong (Box 5)
    - Letter, 3 Mar., 1814, from Philip Turner, New York, to James Madison (Box 5)
    - Letter, 10 Apr., 1814, from Philip Turner, New York, to John Armstrong (Box 5)
    - Letter, 27 June, 1814, from Philip Turner, New York, to James Madison (Box 5)
    - Letter, 27 June, 1814, from Philip Turner, New York, to James Madison (Box 5)
    - Letter, 2 July, 1814, from Philip Turner, New York, to Daniel Parker (Box 5)
    - Letter, 20 July, 1814, from Philip Turner, to the editor of the National Advocate (Box 5)
    - Letter, 29 July, 1814, from Philip Turner, to Francis Le Baron (Box 5)
    - Letter, 18 Aug., 1814, from Philip Turner, New York, to James Madison (Box 5)
    - Letter, 24 Aug., 1814, from Francis Le Baron, New York, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 5 Sept., 1814, from unknown, to Philip Turner (Box 5)
    - Letter, 18 Oct., 1814, from Philip Turner, New York, to James Monroe (Box 5)
    - Letter, 21 Oct., 1814, from Philip Turner, New York, to James Monroe (Box 5)
    - Letter, 18 Nov., 1814, from Philip Turner, New York, to George M. Troup (Box 5)
    - Letter, 2 Feb., 1815, from Philip Turner, New York, to Daniel Parker (Box 5)
    - Letter, undated, from unknown, to Joseph B. Varnum (Box 5)
    - Letter, undated, from Philip Turner, to John Armstrong (Box 5)
  - Manuscripts, 1814-1815, 1830-1831
    - Medicine & Store as per the Class Book of Mr. Cutts (Box 5)
    - Copies of the Orders drawn by Doctor Le Baron, apothecary to Mr. Leefe, druggist, Messrs. Talman and Torry and Major Baron, assistant Quarter-master, 29 July 1814 (Box 5)
    - Logbook, 1814-1815, 1830-1831 (Box 9)